CHAITANYA VARMA

Project Management | Customer Success

09603998252 | gchaitanya.369@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/chaitanya-varmag/

SUMMARY

More than five years of experience performing in technical project management & customer success roles, handling critical technology planning, integration and deployment for various products & services for software development projects using the Agile methodologies. Delivered Smart city, Safe city & city-wide surveillance projects using IoT devices, which enhanced the quality of public life. Contributed to digital platform projects to build an online presence for small to medium-scale companies.

CORE SKILLS & COMPETENCIES

Agile, Waterfall, Kanban & Scrum Methodologies | SDLC | Customer Success & Client Management

HTML | CSS | WordPress | MySQL | Python | JIRA

Marketing Content | Newsletter Templates Designing | Figma

EXPERIENCE

Xavvy, Newcastle Upon Tyne – UK.

(2020 - Present)

CUSTOMER SUCCESS | PROJECT MANAGEMENT

- Initiated and led kick-off meetings to ensure successful project outcomes and foster strong relationships with international clients in a customer success role.
- Managed multiple accounts on various platforms, including e-commerce websites, HRMS Suite, and VISA Immigration services, to provide exceptional customer service and drive business growth.
- Created and delivered technical support, use cases, and customer engagement training to ensure customer satisfaction and retention.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to design and implement UI/UX improvements and streamline processes, resulting in improved customer experience and increased business efficiency.
- Developed marketing content, social media templates, and newsletter templates to promote brand awareness and provide clients with valuable resources to support their success.

Matrix Security & Surveillance, Bangalore - IN.

(2018 - 2020)

TECHNICAL PROJECT MANAGER | PRE-SALES

- Delivered extremely sensitive projects across multiple cities in India using Agile methodology that impacted the everyday lives of the citizen for the better.
- Detailed understanding of the project scope and performed sprint meetings to enhance usability.
- Implemented emergency call response system DIAL100, Integrated Command Control Centre (ICCC) software which helped the police reach the crime scene within seven minutes.
- Built command center at Commissioner's office & installed 10,000+ CCTV cameras with number plate, red light violation & facial recognition analytics & issued body-worn cameras to the law enforcement across Bangalore.
- Slashed project costs by 30% by negotiating pricing & fees while ensuring the continuation and enhancements of services.

PROJECT ENGINEER | BUSINESS DEVELOPMENT

- Operated on Waterfall methodology to commence four bio-diesel fuel stations across the Karnataka state.
- Trained the team & implemented Microsoft Projects to decrease the workload and make them more efficient.
- Associated with the Central Government & prepared permission letters for each oil & gas licensing department saving 30 days in documentation time & speed up the process for clients.
- Leveraged social media campaigns to generate 50 Lakhs in revenue by generating and closing potential leads.
- Provided fuel for testing to potential influencers in the market, we were able to slash the marketing budget of brand awareness by 40%, which enabled us to redirect those resources to other areas that needed attention.

ADDITIONAL COURSES

2022-2023	Front-End Development in MERN Stack – edX Boot Camp United Kingdom. (On-going)
2022-2023	Advanced PG Course for Software Engineering in IoT & Blockchain – IIT Madras. (On-going)
2021	Professional Project Management – Google Project Management.
2018	Mini MBA Course – Swiss eLearning Institute.
EDUCATION	
2012 - 2017	DVDIT HVDEDADAD INDIA

2013 - 2017 BVRIT – HYDERABAD, INDIA

BACHELOR OF TECHNOLOGY IN CHEMICAL ENGINEER.